Hi I'm Kim with Simply Beautiful in Austin, Texas.
Let's talk about how to tan without burning.
Almost impossible.
So what we're going to need to do is build our exposure time in the sun up a little bit at a time, say 10 to 15 minutes a day.
Also important, of course, is sunscreen.
So you want to apply the sunscreen liberally all over your face and body.
Don't forget your chest, your hands, and the tops of your feet.
We're going to just demonstrate on Megan just to show you about how much we want to put on her face.
We're going to use a 15 with Megan because Megan doesn't burn very easily because she has olive colored skin.
Those of you who are more fair are going to want to have higher number sunscreen, so you want to shoot for a 30, 45.
A lot of people don't know but the number on a sunscreen stands for how much longer you can stay in the sun with sunscreen on then without.
So if you burn in 10 minutes you'll be able to stay in 15 times longer than that, or 20 times, or 50 times.
Most people don't really need a 50.
So we're just blending it making sure that we get all the delicate areas.
I don't want you to put sunscreen in your eyes or really closely around your eye area because if there is and it gets in your eyes it'll sting.
So as close to your eye area as you can but not on it.
Don't forget a nice sunblocking lip moisturizer.
They have them with 15 or even 20 sunscreen.